# Agustí Bau Pericón

 $\square$ agustibau@gmail.com  $\square$  +34699540050  $\square$  in/agustibau  $\square$  www.agustibau.com

I see myself as a persistent, results-driven, and easygoing software engineer.

I've worked with multiple languages and adapt quickly to codebases and their patterns.

When I write code, I prioritize meeting business needs, having modular code, followed by tests, and then tidy, maintainable code.

I like to care about the products I build, I want them to be usable by users, bug-free

I enjoy coding in Vim, running Linux, running scripts, and all that madness.

Outside of work, I love mountain biking and highlining.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Senior software Engineer → Tech Lead - Clovr-labs

Jan 2022 - present, Barcelona

I'm part of the chain\* team, where we build a highly scalable blockchain analytics system, mainly using Python, Spark, DeltaLake, BigQuery and Redis, everything on kubernetes.

I've been part of the team since I joined and my responsabilities have been increasing over time. I started as an individual contributor, and my role has evolved into a "tech lead". Today:

- We've designed the architecture of the overall system, I've implemented some critical parts of it
- I'm the communication point our main client, translating requirements into tasks for the team
- I'm the go-to person when we have memory leaks or performance issues
- I try to set standards by practice and example (tidy merge requests, being reliable, taking responsibility of the code I write, acting mature and reasonable)

#### **Senior software Engineer - Kasaz**

Jul 2020 - Jan 2022, Barcelona

We operated fully remote. I did everything required to keep the platform rolling, backend (ruby on rails), frontend (react, react native and graphql) and devops (AWS). I did also onboard and somewhat manage the newcomers that joined the company

Some of the features that we built:

- Search listings by drawing a hand-drawn area or panning the map automatically
- Feed generation to be ingested by traffic providers, involving complex SQL queries that have to run for any amount of listings.
- Alert system to keep users up to date with new listings according to saved searches

## **Startup incubator - Zinc.vc**

Sept 2019 - Feb 2020, London

I was part of "mission 3" where we looked for startup possiblities "for the older population".

## **Software engineer - Datatiger**

Oct 2017 - Nov 2018, London

At Datatiger we built a marketing tool, horizontally scalable following a microservices architecture using mainly Java and Python on Docker and AWS.

- I was the 8th hire, we developed, designed, and architected key main features of the platform.
- I was responsible of integrating our platform with different systems (email providers, other event providers, ad networks, among others).
- I developed the first parts of the analytics system based on a data lake architecture.

### Junior software engineer - King

Jun 2016 - Sep 2017, Barcelona

We developed an internal marketing tool built on Jboss, AWS Redshift and Kafka, using Agile methodologies.

- I implemented end to end image notifications across all King games.
- I developed multiple backend features that incorporated into an ETL process.

#### Remote For Mac - Self-employed

2013 - 2016~

While at university I developed an Android app, a remote control for Mac devices, for Android. Over time it got downloaded over 200k times, and netted some student money. Better competitors appeared and I lost interest.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor's degree in computer science • Barcelona School of Informatics • 2018 • 7.3 (out of 10)